#### Contact

praveeng441@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/praveenkumar-govindu-12a415166 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

HIL Testing
dSPACE Tool Chain

# Praveen Kumar Govindu

Electronics Systems(HIL)Engineer at ZF Group Birmingham, United Kingdom

### Summary

7 years of Experience in Automotive Embedded Systems, Responsible for gathering, analyzing and defining requirements, and delivering embedded software solutions.

Majorly working in both HIL Testing & HIL Commissioning. My expertise is in HIL setup [Commissioning of dSPACE Full size simulators], Manual Testing using dSPACE ControlDeskNG, Test automation using dSPACE AutomationDesk & Python.

Experienced in Validation of Body Control Module, EPAS and Engine Control Module systems.

### Experience

ZF Group Electronics System HIL Engineer November 2018 - Present Solihull, West Midlands, United Kingdom

**HCL** Technologies

Test Lead (HIL Test Engineer/HIL validation Engineer)

August 2015 - October 2018 (3 years 3 months)

Chennai Area, India

Deputed at Client(Ford Motor Pvt Ltd)

Working as HIL testing(Validation) Engineer from August 2015.

DynaFusion Technologies(dSPACE Partner in India) Application Engineer June 2012 - August 2015 (3 years 3 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Worked as a Application Engineer at DynaFusion Technologies Pvt Ltd(Representative of dSPACE).

Responsibilities as HIL engineer were to build the HIL Rigs, IO functionality testing using dSPACE Hardwares/Softwares.

## Education

National Institute of Technology Calicut

Master of Technology - MTech, Electrical and Electronics

Engineering · (2010 - 2012)

VNR Vignanajyothi Institute of Engineering & Technology Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2006 - 2010)